Francis Biddle Collection of International Military Tribunal Nuremberg Trial Documents and Related Material
Francis Biddle Collection of International Military Tribunal Nuremberg Trial Documents and Related Material
- Trial documents
  - International Military Tribunal
    - Trial of The Major War Criminals before the International Military Tribunal; Nuremberg, 14 November 1945 - 1 October 1946; Nuremberg, Germany, International Military Tribunal, 1947; 42 volumes
      - Vol. XXVI, Documents in Evidence, 405-PS to 1063(d)-PS, 705 p. (Vol. 37) (Box 10)
      - Vol. XXVII, Documents in Evidence, 104-PS to 1739-PS, 612 p. (Vol. 38) (Box 10)
      - Vol. XXVIII, Documents in Evidence, 1742-PS to 1849-PS, 603 p. (Vol. 39) (Box 10)
      - Vol. XXIX, Documents in Evidence, 1850-PS to 2233-PS, 725 p. (Vol. 40) (Box 11)
      - Vol. XXX, Documents in Evidence, 2239-PS to 2582-PS, 612 p. (Vol. 41) (Box 11)
      - Vol. XXXI, Documents in Evidence, 2605-PS to 3054-PS, 636 p. (Vol. 42) (Box 11)
      - Vol. XXXII, Documents in Evidence, 3058-PS to 3728-PS, 603 p. (Vol. 43) (Box 11)
      - Vol. XXXIII, Documents in Evidence, 3729-PS to 3993-PS, 594 p. (Vol. 44) (Box 12)
      - Vol. XXXIV, Documents in Evidence, 4004-PS to 195-C, 787 p. (Vol. 45) (Box 12)
      - Vol. XXXV, Documents in Evidence, 039-D to 906-D, 700 p. (Vol. 46) (Box 12)
      - Vol. XXXVI, Documents in Evidence, 908-D to 224-F, 717 p. (Vol. 47) (Box 12)
      - Vol. XXXVII, Documents in Evidence, 257-F to 180-L, 717 p. (Vol. 48) (Box 13)
      - Vol. XXXVIII, Documents in Evidence, 185-L to 1216-RF, 746 p. (Vol. 49) (Box 13)
      - Vol. XXXIX, Documents in Evidence, 1218-RF to JN, 636 p. (Vol. 50) (Box 13)
      - Vol. XL, Documents in Evidence, Bormann-11 to Raeder-7, 607 p. (Vol. 51) (Box 13)
      - Vol. XLI, Documents in Evidence, Raeder-8 to Streicher-21, 560 p. (Vol. 52) (Box 14)
      - Vol. XLII, Documents in Evidence, Col. Neave Report to Affidavit SS-87, 664 p. (Vol. 53) (Box 14)
    - International Commission Against Concentration Camp Practices, Bulletin, December 1955; printed material, 74 p. (Box 14)
    - Memoranda
      See also Additions: Trial documents: Memoranda (Box 19).
      - Memorandum concerning a letter from President Harry S. Truman to Mr. Biddle in answer to Mr. Biddle's report to the President., November 12, 1946; official release; pr. mat (Box 14)
      - Secret memorandum by Herbert Wechsler, Assistant Attorney General, on a War Department Proposal that the German leaders be tried for "Conspiracy to achieve domination of other countries...", December 29, 1944; typescript copy (Box 14)
      - Memorandum to Judge Biddle and Judge Parker regarding organizational problems, October 5, 1945; typescript (Box 14)
      - Memorandum to Judge Biddle and Judge Parker regarding counsel for defendants, October 27, 1945; typescript, Nurnberg (Box 14)
      - Memorandum to Sir David Maxwell-Fyfe, regarding the Indictment, October 16, 1945; typescript (Box 14)
      - Memorandum of General Nikitchenko to the members of the International Military Tribunal, regarding the length of the trial and its effect on public opinion, May 27, 1946; Translation from Russian, typescript copy (Box 14)
      - 2 Memoranda in French by Donnedieu de Vabres, Member of the French Republic, July 8, 1946; regarding the pleas of Mr. Kleefish [undated] and Professor Jahreiss, typescript (Box 14)
      - Fragment of Memorandum initiated by M. de Vabres, July 16, 1946; regarding the technical rules of the law of conspiracy; typescript copy, in French (Box 14)
      - "Memorandum of the Soviet Member IMT", July 17, 1946; regarding the "Conception of Conspiracy", translated from Russian, typescript copy (Box 14)
      - One unsigned and undated memorandum regarding the reduction of the accusation, typescript, in French (Box 14)
      - One recommendation in French, unsigned and undated (Box 14)
    - Index to Rulings of the Tribunal, Rulings of the Tribunal, undated; typescript, 131 p. (cover with "Mr. Justice Biddle" in red removed) (Box 14)
    - Drafts of judgment
      See also Additions: Trial documents: Drafts of judgment (Box 19)
      - Suggested Framework of the Judgment of the Tribunal, undated; typescript copy annotated, 72 p. (Box 14)
      - Views on Count 1, The Common Plan or Conspiracy, undated; typescript copy, 5 p. (Box 14)
      - The Common Plan and Agressive War, undated; Draft A, typescript revised, 48 p. (Box 14)
      - The Common Plan and Agressive War, undated; Draft B, typescript copy revised, 59 p. (Box 14)
      - Fragment, undated; typescript copy, 2p. (Box 14)
    - Notes on judgment
      - Meetings of the Tribunal to discuss Judgment, June 27 - September 26, 1946; typescript, 67p. (Box 14)
    - Appeals from judgment
      - Martin Bormann, October 2, 1946; pr. mat, 7 p. (Box 14)
      - Karl Doenitz, October 3, 1946; printed material, 4 p. (Box 14)
      - Hans Frank, October 4, 1946; printed material, 14p. (Box 14)
      - Wilhelm Frick, October 4, 1946; printed material, 2p. (Box 14)
      - Walter Funk, October 4, 1946; printed material, 6p. (Box 14)
      - Gestapo - Geheime Schutzpolizei, October 5, 1946; printed material, 4 p. (Box 14)
      - Hermann Goering, October 4, 1946; printed material, 4p. (Box 14)
      - Rudolf Hess, October 2, 1946; printed material, 47 p. (Box 14)
      - Alfred Jodl, October 4, 1946; printed material, 14p. (Box 15)
      - Wilhelm Keitel, October 5, 1946; printed material, 2p. (Box 15)
      - Constantin Freiherr von Neurath, October 5, 1946; printed material, 2 p. (Box 15)
      - The Political Leaders Corps, October 5, 1946; printed material, 2p. (Box 15)
      - Erich Raeder, October 4, 1946; printed material, 2 p. (Box 15)
      - Joachim von Ribbentrop, October 4, 1946; printed material,15 p. (Box 15)
      - Alfred Rosenberg, October 3, 1946; printed material, 5 p. (Box 15)
      - Fritz Sauckel, October 5, 1946; printed material, 12p. (Box 15)
      - Baldur von Schirach, October 3, 1946; printed material, 1 p. (Box 15)
      - SD - Sichercheitsdienst, October 4, 1946; printed material, 3 p. (Box 15)
      - Arthur Seyss-Inquart, October 3, 1946; printed material, 18 p. (Box 15)
      - SS - Schutzstaffel, October 2, 1946; printed material, 1 p. (Box 15)
      - Julius Streicher, October 5, 1946; printed material, 2 p. (Box 15)
  - Related documents
    See also Additions: Trial documents: Miscellaneous documents (Box 19)
    - Document relating to the Charter of the Tribunal by Justice Lawrence, undated; typescript copy revised, 7 p. (Box 15)
    - "The Common Plan of Conspiracy", August 13, 1946; typescript, 4 p. (Box 15)
    - Official release on a proposed heraldic design for the U. S. Chief Council, December 13, 1945; printed material, 1 p. (Box 15)
    - Glossary of Legal Terms., undated; French-English, typescript copy, autographed by Mr. Biddle, 66 p. (Box 15)
    - Document regarding protection to defense council against attack from the press. Attached a letter to Dr. Jahreiss, August 2, 1946; typescript, 3 p. (Box 15)
    - "The Instantaneous Multi-Lingual Interpreting System in the International Military Tribunal", undated; typescript copy, 4 p. (Box 15)
    - "Law as to the Accused Organizations", August 9, 1946; typescript, 3 p. (Box 15)
    - Protocol, undated; printed material, 1 p. (Box 15)
    - Rules of the International Military Tribunal., undated; printed material, 4 p. (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous material
    - Dokumentry Obvineniia po delu No. 1., (Documents of Indictment, part 1.) photograph album, publ. in the U.S.S.R., undated captions in English. (Vol. 54) (Box 15)
    - Lager Osventsim, undated; (Camp of the Conquered) photograph album, published material, Publ. in the U.S.S.R. (Vol. 55) (Box 15)
    - Arbeit und Wehr., June 1938; Illustrated newspaper about the German textile industry, published material (Berlin) (Box 15)
    - Katyn Forest Massacre. Congressional Hearings of the Eighty-second Congress, Washington, D.C.
      - First Session (Vol. 56), October 11, 1951 (Box 15)
      - Second Session, Part 2 (Vol. 57), February 4-7, 1952 (Box 15)
      - Second Session, Part 3 (Vol. 58), March 13-14, 1952 (Box 15)
      - Second Session, Part 4 (Vol. 59), April 16-19, 1952 (Box 15)
      - Second Session, Part 5 (Vol. 60), April 21-26, 1952 (Box 15)
      - Second Session, Part 6, Exhibits 32 & 33 (Vol. 61), 1952 (Box 15)
      - Second Session, Part 7 (Vol. 62), June 3-4 and; November 11-14, 1952 (Box 15)
      - Second Session, Interim Report, July 2, 1952 (Box 16)
      - Second Session, Final Report, December 22, 1952 (Box 16)
  - Published material
    - Books
      - The Charter and Judgment of the Nurnberg Tribunal. Memorandum (Vol. 63), March 3, 1949; United Nations Publ. New York (Box 16)
      - Descheemaeker, Jaques. Le Tribunal Militaire International des Grandes Criminels de Guerre (Vol. 64), 1947; Paris; autographed copy (Box 16)
      - Pella, Vespasian V. La Guerre-Crime et les Criminels de Guerre. (Vol. 65), 1946; Geneve (Box 16)
      - Le Proces de Nuremberg: l'Accusation Francaise. (Vol. 66), October 10, 1946; Documents pour servir a l'Histoire de la Guerre, Paris (Box 16)
      - Le Proces de Nuremberg: Exposes Introductifs. (Vol. 67), 1946; Documents pour servir a l' Histoire de la Guerre, Paris (Box 16)
      - Le Proces de Nuremberg: la Responsabilite Individuelle dans la Perpetration des Crimes contre la Paix., July 1946; Societe Egyptienne de Droit International Brochure no. 3 (Box 16)
      - [Taylor, Telford] Final Report to the Secretary of the Army on the Nuernberg War Crimes Trials under Control Council Law No. 10. Washington (Vol. 68), August 15, 1949 (Box 16)
      - Vabres, H. Donnedieu de. Le Proces de Nuremberg devant les principes modernes du droit penal international. (Vol. 69), 1947; Paris, autographed copy (Box 16)
    - Articles and papers
      - Allen, Florence E. "The Nuremberg Trial Implements World Law.", May 1947; reprint from The Educational Forum (Box 16)
      - Biddle, Francis. "The Nurnberg Trials," Virginia Law Review, vol. 33, no. 6, November 1947 (Box 16)
      - Biddle, Francis. "The Nurnberg Trial," R.A.F. Penrose Jr. Memorial Lecture, 1947; reprint from the American Philosophical Society, vol. 91, no. 3 (Box 16)
      - Graven, Jean. "En Assistant au Proces des Criminels de Guerre.", July and; August 1, 1946; reprint from Journal de Geneve (Box 16)
      - Jackson, Robert H. "The Jackson Report," text of statement on the signing of the War Crimes Agreement., August 8 1945; Reprint from The New York Times. London (Box 16)
      - Jackson, Robert H. "Nuremberg in Retrospect: Legal Answer to International Lawlessness," American Bar Association, vol. 35, October 1949 (Box 16)
      - Kempner, Robert M.W. "Review: The Nuremberg Trials as Sources of Recent German Political and Historical Material.", June 1950; reprint from The American Political Science Review, vol. XLIV, no. 2 (Box 16)
      - Leventhal, Harold. "The Nuernberg Verdict.", 1947; reprint from The Harvard Law Review, vol. LX, no. 6 (Box 16)
      - Meltzer, Bernard D. "Comment, a Note on some Aspects of the Nuremberg Debate.", April 1947; reprint from The University of Chicago Law Review, vol. 14, no. 3 (Box 16)
      - [Menthon, Francais de.] "Le Proces de Nuremberg.", January 17, 1946 (Box 16)
      - Morris, James. "Major War Crimes Trials in Nurnberg," North Dakota Bar Briefs, vol. 25, no. 2, April 1949 (Box 16)
      - Mossler, Hermann. "Comments on document entitled: 'International Legal Evaluation of the Norway Action'", April 6, 1946; typescript (Box 16)
      - Schact, Hjalmar. "The Nuernberg Trial," excerpt from "Settlement with Hitler", undated; typescript copy (Box 16)
      - Schact, Hjalmar. "Abrechnung mit Hitler". Hamburg, Germany, Rowohlt Verlag, October 1948 (Box 16)
      - Schact, Hjalmar. "The Nuernberg Trial (Excerpt from settlement with Hitler)", typescript copy, 13 p. (English translation) (Box 16)
      - Szilard, Leo. "My Trial as a War Criminal", November 11, 1947; fiction; typescript copy (Box 17)
      - (Taylor, Telford) "Did the International Tribunals Convict Germany of Waging Agressive War Against 10 or 12 Other Nations?,", May 9, 1950; typescript copy (Box 17)
      - Taylor, Telford. "The Nazis go Free," The Nation, February 24, 1951 (Box 17)
      - Taylor, Telford. "Robert H. Jackson and the Nuremberg Trials.", April 1955; reprint from the Columbia Law Review, vol. 55 (Box 17)
      - Walkingshaw, Robert B. "The Nuremberg and Tokyo Trials: Another Step Towards International Justice," American Bar Association Journal, vol. 35, April 1949> (Box 17)
      - Wechsler, Herbert. "The Issues of the Nuremberg Trial," Political Science Quarterly, vol. LXII, no. 1, March 1947 (Box 17)
      - (Wechsler, Herbert) "Memoirs of a Conference with President Benes", February 16, 1946; typescript copy; Mr. Wechsler describes a visit with Mr. Sidney Alderman to Dr. Benes in Prague, February 5, 1946, in which Dr. Benes recalls a conversation with President Roosevelt in 1939. (Box 17)
      - Wechsler, Herbert. Remarks made before the showing of the film "Nuremberg - Its Lesson for To-day, for the Association of American Law Schools, Chicago, December 28, 1950; published material (Box 17)
      - Wright, Robert Alderson. "Nuremberg", statement on the judgment., August 15, 1947; published material (London) (Box 17)
      - Wright, Quincy. "Legal Positivism and the Nuremberg Judgment," The American Journal of International Law, undated (Box 17)
      - Wright, Quincy. "Some Important Events in 1946; The Nuremberg Trial.", March-April 1947; reprint from the Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology of Northwestern University, vol. 37, No. 6 (Box 17)
- Miscellaneous documents
  - Published material
    - Badkowski, Antoni. Les Problemes de la Sauvegarde de la paix et de la Liqudation des Suites de Guerrexau Point de Vue du Droit Polonais., 1947; Brussels (Box 17)
    - Cowles, Willard B. "Universality of Jurisdiction over War Criminals.", June 1945; reprint from California Law Review, vol. XXXIII, no. 2 (Box 17)
    - "Guerre de 1939, Crimes de Guerre." Gour de Cassation, June 3, 1950. Jurisprudence (Box 17)
    - Jackson, Robert H. Address delivered before the American Society of International Law. Washington, D.C.., April 13, 1945 (Box 17)
    - Levy, Albert G.D. "The Law and Prodedure of War Crime Trials.", December 1943; reprint from The American Political Review, vol. XXXVII, no. 6 (Box 17)
    - Pella, Vespasian V. "Federalism and Regionalism.", October 1950; reprint from Common Cause: a Journal of One World, vol. 4, no. 3, autographed copy (Box 17)
    - Pella, Vespasian V. "The International Association of Penal Law and the Safeguarding of Peace"., 1947; (French Text and English Sukmary) Paris (Box 17)
    - Radin, Max. "International Crimes.", November 1946; reprint from The Iowa Law Review, vol. 32, no. 1, autographed copy (Box 17)
    - La Revue de Droit International: de Sciences Deplomatiques et Politiques. "Cour Penale Internationale et Code repressif des Nations," by Megalos A. Caloyanni. Geneve, extract no. 4 (1945) (Box 17)
    - Revue de Droit Penal et de Criminology. "The Nuremberg Trial" by Francis Biddle. Reprint from the American Philosophical Society. Brussels, no. 6, March 1948 (Box 17)
    - Revue Egyptienne de Droit International. Sommaire. 1945., November 14, 1945; Autographed by the ed., Alexandria (Box 17)
    - Revue Internationale de Droit Penal (Paris)
      - No's 2-4, 1948 (Box 17)
      - No's 1-4, 1949 (Box 17)
      - No. 2, 1950 (Box 17)
      - No's 3, 4, 1950 (Box 18)
      - No's 1-2, 1954 (Box 18)
    - Sottile, Antoine. The Problem of the Creation of a Permanent International Criminal Court., 1951; Extract from Revue de Droit Internationales, no. 4, Geneve (Box 18)
    - Tables Analytiques: de l' Annee 1953 Revue Internationale de Droit Penal., undated; Paris (Box 18)
    - Wehle, Louis B. "Comparative Law's Proper Task for the International Court.", October 1950; reprint from the University of Pennsylvania Law Review, vol. 99, no. 1 (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "Changes in International Law and the Concepts of War and Aggression.", June 27, 1944; ts. (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "Collective Rights and Duties for the Enforcment of Treaty Obligations.", April 28-30, 1932; reprint from the American Society of International Law, Proceedings (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "The Concepts of Aggression in International Law.", July 1935; reprint from the American Journal of International Law, vol. 29, no. 3 (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "Congress and the Treaty-Making Powers.", 1952; reprint from the Proceedings from The American Society of International Law (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "The Crime of 'War-Mongering'," The American Journal of International Law, undated (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "The Interpretation of Multilateral Treaties," The American Journal of International Law, undated (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "International Law and the Totalitarian States.", August 1941; reprint from The American Science Review, vol. XXXV, no. 4 (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "The Lend-Lease Bill and International Law," The American Journal of International Law, undated (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "Neutrality and Neutral Rights Following the Pact of Paris for the Renunciation of War.", 1930; reprint from the American Society of International Law, Proceedings (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "The Path to Peace," World Unity Magazine, undated (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "Peace Problems of Today and Yesterday.", June 1944; reprint from The American Political Science Review, vol. XXXVIII, no. 3 (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "Permissive Sanction against Aggression," The American Journal of International Law, undated (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "The Present Status of Neutrality," The American Journal of International Law, undated (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "Responsibility for Injuries to United Nations Officials," The American Journal of International Law, undated (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "Rhineland Occupation and the Enforcement of Treaties.", July 1936; reprint from the American Journal of International Law, vol. 30, no. 3 (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "The Test of Aggression in the Italo-Ethiopian War.", January 1936; reprint from The American Journal of International Law, vol. 30, no. 1 (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "Law Reports of Trials of War Criminals, Vol. II: The Belsen Trial.", May-June 1948; reprint from the Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology of Northwestern University, vol. 39, no. 1 (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "Law Reports of Trials of War Criminals.", May-June 1949; reprint from the Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology of Northwestern University, vol. 40, no. 1 (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. "Law Reports of Trials of War Criminals.", January-February 1950; reprint from the Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology of Northwestern University, vol. 40, no. 5 (Box 18)
    - Wright, Quincy. Review of Book by M. Donnedieu de Vabres entitled Les Principes Modernes du Droit Penal International. Paris, 1928, undated; typescript, typescript copy (Box 18)
    - Trial of Japanese War Criminals., documents (Box 18)
- Additions
  - Personal papers
    - Correspondence
      - Francis Biddle to Katherine Chapin Biddle (wife) and Edmund Randolph ("Randy") Biddle (son)
        - Originals, 1945 Oct-Nov; 1946 Feb-Mar, May-Aug; two separately numbered sequences, both incomplete, which are here interfiled; letters were written mostly from Nuremberg and constitute a journal; 9 folders (Box 19)
        - Transcripts, typed (incomplete set), 1945-1946; includes transcripts of some letters not found in the preceding 9 folders (Box 19)
      - Mary O'B. Johnson (Judge Biddle's secretary) to Katherine Chapin Biddle, 1945-1946; 5 items (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1945-1949 (Box 19)
        Includes letters to Francis Biddle from Mary McLeod Bethune and Leroy H. Watson; carbons of letters from Francis Biddle to George Biddle (brother), General Eisenhower (1945 Oct 30), President Truman (1946 Jan 5 and 1946 Nov 9), and Robert Jackson; a letter in French from Robert Martin to "monsieur le juge" [Parker?]; and an exchange of letters (6 items), 1948-1949, between Francis Biddle and Hans Lamm
    - "The Nürnberg Trial," ms. of Francis Biddle's autobiography, Book Four, vol. 2, In Brief Authority, ca. 1960; annotated typescript, chapters 25-32 (pages 563-724); 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Trial documents
    - Drafts of judgment
      See also Trial documents: International Military Tribunal: Drafts of judgement, above.
      - Suggestion for Skeleton Opinion, 1946 May 9; typescript copy, 5 pp. (Box 19)
      - Sir Norman Birkett's draft, 1946 Jun 7; typescript; Document one, Suggested framework of the judgment, in bare outline, [10]pp.; Document two, Suggested framework of the judgment of the Tribunal, 42 pp.); Note to accompany documents one and two, 2 pp. (Box 19)
      - Francis Biddle's drafts
        - 1946 Jun 27, typescript copy, 11 pp. (2 copies) (Box 19)
        - 1946 Aug 28, annotated typescript copy, 12 pp. ("3d Draft") (Box 19)
        - 1946 Sep 2, typescript copy, 13pp. ("Fourth Draft") (2 copies) (Box 19)
        - 1946 Sep 2, typescript copy, [24]pp. ("Quatrième projet") French translation of the fourth draft (2 copies) (Box 19)
      - Note to accompany document, undated; annotated typescript copy, [7]pp. and typescript, 6 pp.; 2 copies (Box 19)
    - Memoranda, 1945 Oct-Nov; 5 items (Box 19)
      See also Trial documents: International Military Tribunal: Memoranda, above.
      Memorandum by James Rowe, Jr. to the American members of the International Military Tribunal on the judges' offices and residences; typescript copy, 3 pp. and 2 duplicate pages; October 25, 1945
      Memorandum by Herbert Wechsler to Judge Biddle and Judge Parker on rates of compensation for German lawyers and judges, the freezing of defendants' assets, and other matters; typescript copy, 1 p.; October 30, 1945
      Memorandum by Francis Biddle to Mr. Justice Jackson on the delay of the judge's arrival in Berlin; typescript copy, 2 pp.; October 30, 1945
      Memorandum by Herbert Wechsler to Colonel Gill transferring a memo to Mr. Justice Jackson from "General Biddle."; typescript copy, 1 p.; October 31, 1945
      Memorandum by Herbert Wechsler to Judge Biddle on procedures for the production of a witness or a document; typescript, 3 pp.; November 9, 1945
    - Memoranda (missing 2 items, 8/7/2012), 1946 Feb-Apr; 3 items (Box 19)
      Memorandum by Herbert Wechsler to Mr. Justice Birkett on procedural questions and Justice Birkett's "Note on Procedure."; typescript copy, 4 pp.; February 19, 1946 [missing 8/7/2012]
      Memorandum by Herbert Wechsler on "The form of the judgment and opinion (Comment on the President's memorandum)."; typescript copy, 8 pp; April 12, 1946 [missing 8/7/2012]
      Memorandum by Herbert Wechsler on "Conspiratorial and accessorial liability under the charter."; typescript, [21] pp.; April 25, 1946
    - Memoranda, 1946 Jun-Sep; 11 items (Box 19)
      Memorandum, unsigned, on editing documents for the first conference; typescript, 1 p.; June 11, 1946
      Memorandum by James H. Rowe, Jr. to Judge Biddle on the judge's draft memorandum on the law of aggressive war; typescript, 1 p.; July 10, 1946
      Memorandum, "Comments by James Rowe on Judge Parker's memorandum."; typescript copy, 7 pp.; July 11, 1946
      Memorandum by James H. Rowe, Jr. to Judge Biddle, "Comments on FB's Second Draft (7/11/46)."; typescript, 2 pp.; July 19, 1946
      Memorandum by James H. Rowe to Judges Biddle and Parker on security; typescript, 2 pp.; July 19, 1946
      Memorandum, "Comments by James Rowe on Justice Birkett's Draft No. 2."; typescript, 8 pp.; July 26, 1946